hannaford.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy and Security | Hannaford

Hannaford Supermarkets ("Hannaford") respects your concerns about privacy. This Privacy Notice applies to personal information we collect on Hannaford.com **** (the "Site"). ****

This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on the Site, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. The Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the personal information. We also tell you how you can reach us to ask us to update your preferences regarding how we communicate with you or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices. 

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

> Information We Collect >>   
>         Information You Provide Directly to Us >>  
>         Information We Collect by Automated Means >>  
>  How We Use the Information We Collect >>  
>  Information We Share >>  
>  Your Choices >>  
>  How We Protect Personal Information >>  
>  Links to Other Websites >>  
>  Children’s Privacy >>  
>  Updates to Our Privacy Notice >>  
>  How to Contact Us >>  
>  Social Media Privacy Policy >>  
>         Ratings and Reviews Service, message boards, blogs, chat rooms, and other forums >>  
>         Violations >>

## Information You Provide Directly to Us

You may provide personal information directly to us, including:

  * Contact information, such as your name, postal address, telephone number, and email address
  * Names, postal addresses and telephone numbers of other people to whom you would like us to send shipments
  * Your favorite products and recipes and the location of your preferred Hannaford stores
  * Transaction numbers from Hannaford store receipts (which enables us to associate your hannaford.com account with the purchases on the receipts) 
  * Health concerns, such as specific food allergies, or nutrition questions
  * Household information, such as the number of people in your family and the number of children you have 
  * Names and birthdays of people you know (in the birthday reminder section)
  * Payment information, such as your credit or debit card number and expiration date
  * Gift card number 
  * Questions, communications and other content you submit
  * Hannaford.com login credentials, such as your password and Mobile Sign-In ID, and your answer to a security question, such as your pet’s name
  * A record of your store transactions when you scan your myHannaford number.
  * Job application information, including current salary; desired salary; answers to online interview questions; whether you are under 18 years of age and, if so, your age; references; education history; employment status and history; and criminal, discipline, suspension or discharge history 

## Information We Collect by Automated Means 

When you visit our Site, we may collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, Web server logs and Web beacons.

Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings in your browser. Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our Site. 

In conjunction with the gathering of information through cookies, our Web servers may log information such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. The Web server logs also may record information such as the address of the Web page that referred you to our Site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. They may also log information about your interaction with this Site, such as which pages you visit.

To control which Web servers collect information by automated means, we may place tags on our Web pages called "Web beacons," which are small files that link Web pages to particular Web servers and their cookies. 

We may use third-party web analytics services on our Site, such as those of Google Analytics. These service providers use cookies and web beacons to help us analyze how users use the Site. The information collected by the cookies and Web beacons (including your IP address) will be disclosed to these service providers, who use the information to evaluate your use of the Site. ****

## How We Use the Information We Collect 

We may use the information we obtain about you when you visit the Site to:

  * Provide, administer and communicate with you about products, services, events and promotions (including by sending you newsletters and other marketing communications)
  * Administer contests, sweepstakes and surveys 
  * Process your purchases and payments
  * Process, evaluate and respond to your requests, inquiries and applications
  * Create, administer and communicate with you about your account
  * Customize your experience with our Site, such as by providing personalized product information, purchase information, coupons and birthday reminders
  * Verify your identity
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; performing market research and data analytics; determining and managing the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing; analyzing our products, services and websites; administering our websites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities) 
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure and quality 
  * If you submit information as a job applicant, evaluate your interest in employment and contact you regarding possible employment 
  * Comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies and terms, such as our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://www.hannaford.com/custserv/custserv.jsp?pageName=Terms)

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection. 

This Site allows you to create and print a customized shopping list. When you print this shopping list, it will include a barcode that you may choose to scan at a Hannaford store register. This barcode uniquely identifies your purchases with your hannaford.com account so that we have the ability to offer you benefits such as customized coupons, product recall information, reports for items purchased that qualify for health care reimbursement, reports for tax deductible donations, and other special benefits. We also may use information gathered through use of this barcode in conjunction with the other purposes described above. 

## **Information We Share**

We may share personal information we collect on this website or through the scanning of your myHannaford number with our service providers companies who perform services on our behalf (such as printing or mailing) if they need this information to perform their services.. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements.  We may share personal information we collect on this website at your request. For example, if you purchase a gift card and ask us to send it to a third party, we may identify you as the sender of the gift card. 

We also may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Statement. 

## **Your Choices**

You may amend your preferences regarding how we communicate with you by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in an email you receive from us or **** by contacting us as described in the "How to Contact Us" section below. If you have created a job applicant profile in our careers section, you access the Edit Profile page of that section to modify the personal information associated with your profile and indicate whether you would like to receive emails about jobs that may interest you. 

## How We Protect Personal Information

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect the personal information you provide on our Site against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use and other unlawful forms of processing.

##  Links to Other Sites 

This Site may provide links to other sites for your convenience and information. These websites may be operated by companies not affiliated with us. Linked websites may have their own privacy policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with us, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

## Children’s Privacy

This website is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the site. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on this site, we will delete the information from our records.

## Updates to Our Privacy Notice 

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices or relevant laws. 

## How to Contact Us 

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us as indicated below. If you are contacting us by email to request that we change or delete personal information that you submitted through our Site, please be sure to tell us which page or form on the Site you used to submit your information:

**Customer Information Center**   
If you have any questions or comments about these the Online Privacy Policy or this Site, [please contact us](http://www.hannaford.com/content.jsp?pageName=CustomerService&leftNavArea=AboutLeftNav). 

**Hannaford Supermarkets**  
145 Pleasant Hill Road  
Scarborough, Maine 04074  
(800) 213-9040

Hannaford Supermarkets is owned by Hannaford Bros. Co., 145 Pleasant Hill Road, Scaborough, Maine, 04074.

On certain areas of our Site, you may be able to interact with other users or upload messages or other content, including videos ("Content"). We may terminate your account and your ability to upload Content if we believe, in our sole discretion, that you have violated any of the terms in these Terms and Conditions, or any law.

By submitting any Content to Hannaford Bros. Co., you represent and warrant that: (i) you are the sole author and owner of the intellectual property rights thereto; (ii) all content that you post is accurate; (iii) you are at least 13 years old; (iv) that use of the Content you supply does not violate these terms of use and will not cause injury to any person or entity; and (v) the Content does not contain viruses, corrupted files, or any other similar software or programs that may adversely affect the operation of the Site or another user’s computer.

You are prohibited from posting or transmitting any false, inaccurate, misleading, unlawful, threatening, libelous, defamatory, obscene, scandalous, inflammatory, pornographic, or profane Content or any Content that could constitute or encourage conduct that would be considered a criminal offense, give rise to civil liability, or otherwise violate any law. Hannaford Bros. Co. will fully cooperate with any law enforcement authorities or court order requesting or directing Hannaford Bros. Co. to disclose the identity of or help identify or locate anyone posting any such Content.

You agree that you will not post Content that contains personal information about any individual, violates the privacy of any other individual or entity, or anything that you are under a contractual obligation to keep private or confidential. You agree that you will not impersonate any person or organization, including without limitation, an employee of Hannaford Bros. Co.. You further agree that you will not misrepresent an affiliation with another person or organization, nor will you post any Content that infringes any copyright, trademark, patent, trade secret or other intellectual property right of a third party.

You agree to indemnify and hold Hannaford Bros. Co. (and its officers, directors, agents, subsidiaries, joint ventures, employees and third-party service providers), harmless from all claims, demands, and damages (actual and consequential) of every kind and nature, known and unknown including reasonable attorneys’ fees, arising out of a breach of your representations and warranties set forth above, or your violation of any law or the rights of a third party.

Although Hannaford Bros. Co. may from time to time monitor or review discussion, chats, postings, transmissions, bulletin boards, and the like on the Site, Hannaford Bros. Co. is under no obligation to do so and assumes no responsibility or liability arising from the content of any such locations or for any error, defamation, libel, slander, omission, falsehood, obscenity, pornography, profanity, danger or inaccuracy contained in any information within such locations on the Site. Hannaford Bros. Co. assumes no responsibility or liability for any actions or communications by you or any unrelated third party within or outside of this Site.

Any communication or material you transmit to the Site by e-mail or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions, or the like is, and will be treated as, nonconfidential and non-proprietary with no obligation of confidence on the part of Hannaford Bros. Co., its agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, partners or third party service providers and their respective directors, officers and employees. Hannaford Bros. Co. cannot prevent the "harvesting" of information from this Site, and you may be contacted by Hannaford Bros. Co. or unrelated third parties, by e-mail or otherwise, within or outside of this Site. Furthermore, Hannaford Bros. Co. is free to use any ideas, concepts, know-how, or techniques contained in any communication you send to the Site for any purpose whatsoever including, but not limited to, developing, manufacturing and marketing products using such information without any compensation to the person sending such information. 

## Ratings and Reviews Service, message boards, blogs, chat rooms, and other forums

The Ratings and Reviews Service, message boards, blogs, chat rooms, and other forums (collectively, the "Boards") we may provide on this Site are intended to allow information exchanges, and for users to express their opinions. We encourage you to interact with the site by reading and commenting on our postings. Here are some additional ground rules to the items that we will post:

Not all posts will be published. We reserve the right to review all submissions and to refuse to post any submission for any reason, in its sole discretion.

We do not guarantee that you will have any recourse through Hannaford Bros. Co. to edit or delete any Content you have submitted. However, we reserve the right to remove or to refuse to post any submission for any reason. You acknowledge that you, not Hannaford Bros. Co., are responsible for the contents of your submission.

The purpose of the Boards is to focus on Hannaford Bros. Co. products. Accordingly, we will not post or comment on Hannaford Bros. Co. policies or rumors, or on our competitors‚ products, marketing strategies or players that endorse their products. We prefer to keep the topics related to Hannaford Bros. Co. equipment and players.

We will offer links to some other websites. While many of these links will be to sites with which we have no commercial or other relationship, some links will be to websites where we have purchased advertisements.

We will not post any Content that contains business solicitation of any type, including advertising a product or service, offering a product or service for sale, or directing readers to a location for more information about a product or service, or for which you have been compensated or granted consideration by any third party.

We will not post any Content that includes any information that references other websites, addresses, email addresses, contact information or phone numbers.

By submitting your email address in connection with your rating and review, you agree that Hannaford Bros. Co. and its third party service providers may use your email address to contact you about the status of your review and other administrative purposes.

We may occasionally edit some postings according to these policies. For more information, please click here for our Legal Notice.

## Violations

If you believe that Content was posted in violation of these Terms and Conditions, please contact us via our Service Feedback form. We may, but typically will not, acknowledge receipt of your complaint.

You agree that we cannot and will not act as arbiter of disputes arising from third party communications or transmission to the Site, but will take only such action as we believe are appropriate in our sole discretion.

If you are a copyright owner and you believe your rights have been violated by Content uploaded to this Site, please follow our Proprietary Rights Complaint Process below. 

Any Content you submit on this website containing artwork, audio recordings, copy, ideas, images, music, photography, text, video recordings, written materials and/or other materials is governed by these terms.

You hereby grant to Hannaford Bros. Co. an irrevocable, non-exclusive, royalty-free perpetual license to use and exploit the Content, including, without limitation, the title(s) and each and every element of the Content, in whole or in part, in any and all manner and media throughout the world. You hereby acknowledge and agree that: (a) Hannaford Bros. Co. shall have the right to edit, alter or arrange the Content in any way it desires in its sole discretion; (b) Hannaford Bros. Co. shall not have any obligation to provide you with any credit when using your Content; and (c) you waive any "moral rights" that you may have in the Content. You understand that Hannaford Bros. Co. will act in reliance upon your grant of rights, representations, warranties and indemnities in this Agreement and may incur substantial expense in reliance upon this grant of rights, representations, warranties and indemnities should Hannaford Bros. Co. use your Content.
